{
    "questions": [
        {
            "options": [
              "B. 72%",
              "C. 82%",
              "D. 85%"
            ],
            "question": "As per the data of 2011 population census, the literacy rate in Assam is approximatelyA. 68%",
            "answer": "B. 72%"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. 1948",
              "C. 1958",
              "D. 1967"
            ],
            "question": "When did Transport Department of Assam was established?A. 1935",
            "answer": "B. 1948"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Hojai and Barpeta",
              "C. Nagaon and Morigaon",
              "D. Kukrajhar and Golaghat"
            ],
            "question": "The major reserves of limestone are in _____ andA. Dima Hasao and Karbi Anglong"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. 24",
              "C. 26",
              "D. 10"
            ],
            "question": "Population wise rank of Assam among the states of India isA. 15"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Second",
              "C. Third",
              "D. Fourth"
            ],
            "question": "The rank of Assam in terms of crude oil production is _____.A. First",
            "answer": "B. Second"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Bhutan and Bangladesh",
              "C. China, Myanmar, Bhutan and Bangladesh",
              "D. Myanmar and Bangladesh"
            ],
            "question": "Assam share international border with which of the following countriesA. Myanmar, Bhutan and Bangladesh",
            "answer": "B. Bhutan and Bangladesh"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Sunderlal Bahuguna",
              "C. Jadav Payeng",
              "D. Kallen Pakkudan"
            ],
            "question": "Who is famously known as the “Forest Man of India”?A. Mike Pandey",
            "answer": "C. Jadav Payeng"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Pobitora Wildlife Sanctuary",
              "C. Garampani Wildlife Sanctuary",
              "D. Chakrasila Wildlife Sanctuary"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following protected areas in Assam is known for Golden LangurA. Nameri National Park",
            "answer": "D. Chakrasila Wildlife Sanctuary"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. 10 February, 2003",
              "D. 20 June, 2005"
            ],
            "question": "When did B. T.A. D was established ?A. 30 November, 2004",
            "answer": "B. 10 February, 2003"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. 27",
              "C. 32",
              "D. 34"
            ],
            "question": "The total number of administrative districts in Assam is _________.A. 23",
            "answer": "D. 34"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. 33",
              "C. 80",
              "D. 126"
            ],
            "question": "The total number of seats in the legislative council of Assam is \t.A. 13",
            "answer": "D. 126"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Rubber",
              "C. Maize",
              "D. Paddy"
            ],
            "question": "Assam is not a traditional growing area of which of the following crop?A. Tobacco"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Mikir Hills",
              "C. Singrimari Hills",
              "D. Makum"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following is the largest Coalfield in Assam?A. Dilli Jaypore",
            "answer": "D. Makum"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 14",
              "B. 24",
              "C. 34",
              "D. 44"
            ],
            "question": "The percentage of population living in urban areas in Assam according to 2011 census is",
            "answer": "A. 14"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. 20.6 %",
              "C. 22.4 %",
              "D. 34.21 %"
            ],
            "question": "How much land of assam has been occupied by forests?A. 17.2 %",
            "answer": "D. 34.21 %"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Kokrajhar",
              "C. Baks",
              "D. Cachar"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following districts of Assam does not have any international boundary?A. Dhemaji"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Kumri Beel Lake",
              "C. Cahndubi Lake",
              "D. Deepor Beel"
            ],
            "question": "Which of is the largest wetland in Assam?A. Sonbill Lake"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. 2007",
              "C. 2008",
              "D. 2009"
            ],
            "question": "In which year Kaziranga National Park became a Tiger reserve?A. 2006"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Borgang",
              "C. Jhanji",
              "D. Bhugdoi"
            ],
            "question": "Which is the northward flow sub-river of Brahmaputra?A. Ronga Noi",
            "answer": "C. Jhanji"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. 1867",
              "C. 1889",
              "D. 1901"
            ],
            "question": "In which of the following year Coal was discovered in Assam?A. 1825"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Guwahati",
              "B. Bongaigaon",
              "C. Numalighar",
              "D. Makum"
            ],
            "question": "Asia’s first successful mechanically drilled oil well was drilled in ________ of Assam way back in 1867.",
            "answer": "D. Makum"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Majuli Island",
              "C. Brahmaputrd Floodplains of Eastern Assam",
              "D. BTAD gred near Bhutan Himalayan foothills"
            ],
            "question": "Red Laterite Soils are found in which of the following areas in AssamA. Karbi Hills and Dima Hasao"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. 720 km",
              "C. 920 km",
              "D. 2880 km"
            ],
            "question": "The length of Brahmaputra within Assam is ______.A. 640 km",
            "answer": "B. 720 km"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. 55%",
              "C. 75%",
              "D. 85%"
            ],
            "question": "The approximate share of Assam in India’s annually production of tea isA. 25%",
            "answer": "B. 55%"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Kaziranga National Park",
              "C. Orang National Park",
              "D. Manas National Park"
            ],
            "question": "Which National Park in Assam is one of the last strongholds for the wild water buffalo?A. Dibru-Saikhowa National Park",
            "answer": "B. Kaziranga National Park"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Sonai Rupai WLS",
              "C. Bornodi WLS",
              "D. Garampani WLS"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following is the oldest among the present eighteen wildlife sanctuaries in Assam?A. Pobitord WLS",
            "answer": "D. Garampani WLS"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Nagaon",
              "C. Tinisuki",
              "D. Nalbari"
            ],
            "question": "The literacy rate of which of the following districts is highest in Assam?A. Kamrup Metropolitan"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. 67.27%",
              "C. 78.81%",
              "D. 88.90%"
            ],
            "question": "Literacy rate of women in assam according to 2011 census?A. 65.21%",
            "answer": "B. 67.27%"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. 1972",
              "C. 1974",
              "D. 1975"
            ],
            "question": "When Assam’s Kaziranga was declared as a national park ?A. 1950",
            "answer": "C. 1974"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. 1849",
              "C. 1859",
              "D. 1869"
            ],
            "question": "In which year a earthquake sank the bank of the Barak by 15 ft.?A. 1839",
            "answer": "D. 1869"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Laikei peak",
              "C. Danbukosu peak",
              "D. Mahadev"
            ],
            "question": "What is the highest peak of Karbi hill ?A. Singhason"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Equator",
              "C. Tropic of Capricorn",
              "D. None of the above"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following geographical lines passes through the state of Assam?A. Tropic of cancer",
            "answer": "D. None of the above"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Tezpur",
              "C. Jorhat",
              "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "Assam’s newest district Majuli is carved out of which of district?A. Dibrugarh",
            "answer": "C. Jorhat"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Mushalpur",
              "C. Barpeta Road",
              "D. Goreswar"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following is the district Headquarter of newly created Baksa District.A. Tamulpur",
            "answer": "B. Mushalpur"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Dhansiri",
              "C. Manas",
              "D. Sonai"
            ],
            "question": "Which among the following is not a principal tributary of Brahmaputra?A. Subansiri",
            "answer": "D. Sonai"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "B. Meghalaya",
              "C. Nagaland",
              "D. None of the above"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following North Eastern state shares the longest boundary with Assam?A. Mizoram",
            "answer": "B. Meghalaya"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Guwahati",
              "B. Itanagar",
              "C. Dispur",
              "D. Agartala"
            ],
            "question": "What is the capital of Assam?",
            "answer": "C. Dispur"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Nilachal Hill",
              "B. Chitrachal Hill",
              "C. Sandhyachal Hill",
              "D. Jogini Hill"
            ],
            "question": "In which hill top, the Kamakhya Temple is located?",
            "answer": "A. Nilachal Hill"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Bishnuram Medhi",
              "B. Tarun Ram Phukan",
              "C. Gopinath Bordoloi",
              "D. None of the Above"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first Chief Minister of Assam?",
            "answer": "C. Gopinath Bordoloi"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1671",
              "B. 1644",
              "C. 1678",
              "D. 1643"
            ],
            "question": "The war of Saraighat was fought between Ahom and Mughal in the year?",
            "answer": "A. 1671"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Jorhat",
              "B. Sualkuchi",
              "C. Diphu",
              "D. Digboi"
            ],
            "question": "Which town is also known as the Manchester of Assam?",
            "answer": "B. Sualkuchi"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1458",
              "B. 1549",
              "C. 1449",
              "D. 1464"
            ],
            "question": "Srimanta Sankardev was born in the year __.",
            "answer": "C. 1449"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 34",
              "B. 32",
              "C. 25",
              "D. 33"
            ],
            "question": "Total number of Districts in Assam are __.",
            "answer": "A. 34"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Godadhar Singha",
              "B. Rudra Singha",
              "C. Siva Singha",
              "D. Pramatta Singha"
            ],
            "question": "The Temple of Umananda was built by:",
            "answer": "A. Godadhar Singha"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. The Mahabharata",
              "B. The Harshacharita",
              "C. The Kalika Purana",
              "D. The Arthashastra"
            ],
            "question": "One of the following books is the most important literature source for the study of early history of Assam. Which is the book?",
            "answer": "C. The Kalika Purana"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Mahiranga Danava",
              "B. Narakasura",
              "C. Bhaskara Varman",
              "D. Naranarayana"
            ],
            "question": "The earliest king of Assam was",
            "answer": "A. Mahiranga Danava"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Palas",
              "B. Varmans",
              "C. Narakas",
              "D. Salastambhas"
            ],
            "question": "The earliest historical dynasty of Assam was that of",
            "answer": "B. Varmans"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Autobiographical writings of the Ahom rulers",
              "B. Diaries written by the monarchs",
              "C. Chronicles",
              "D. None of the above"
            ],
            "question": "The Buranjis are",
            "answer": "C. Chronicles"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Bhagadatta",
              "B. Kumar Bhaskar Barman",
              "C. Swargadeo Rudra Singha",
              "D. Kumar Rudra Barman"
            ],
            "question": "Hiuen Tsang visited Assam (kamarupa) in 640 AD. He was received by the king",
            "answer": "B. Kumar Bhaskar Barman"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 13th century",
              "B. 14th century",
              "C. 15th century",
              "D. 10th century"
            ],
            "question": "Ibn Battuta, the celebrated traveler visited Assam in the",
            "answer": "B. 14th century"
          }
    ]
}